

SAMUELE BATTISTELLA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



Via Alessandro Manzoni, 7, 21040, Gornate Olona (VA), Italy



(+39)3494639954



samuele.battistella92@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I'm a software developer focused on a frontend development, expecially with the React framework. I also have experience as backend development and mobile development.

I consider myself a versatile and curious guy, this has allowed me to experiment different technologies and development areas.

In work, I look for quality, precision and motivations to increase my skills.

SKILLS

Frontend

Languages and framework:

- React
- Javascript
- Typescript
- HTML
- · CSS

Backend

Languages and framework:

- Flixir
- Phoenix framework
- NodeJS
- Express

DBMS:

- Postgres
- MongoDB
- Elasticsearch
- TimescaleDB

Technologies:

- Docker
- Nginx
- AWS: EC2, ECS, SQS and S3
- Architectures: microservices and CQRS/ES

Mobile

iOS

- Objective-C
- Swift

Android:

Java

Crossplatform:

ReactNative

Agile software development: scrum and kanban

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BACKEND DEVELOPER

Athonet srl | 04/2020 - 12/2021

Elixir backend developer and occasionally frontend React developer for a USIMs management software and a traffic monitoring system for private LTE networks. The software was deployed on a cloud platform (AWS), and on premise, for customers who need customization like ENEL.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Freelancer | 05/2019 - 03/2020

Development of two simulation web platform with admin dashboard, built with React and NodeJS, for the administration of hospital ward and machines, commisionate by General Eletric Healtcare.

Development of an acquisition and video manipulation software for industrial engine overhaul for Rimac s.r.l.

Development of website and admin dashboard for Gornate Olona kindergarten.

MOBILE DEVELOPER

D-Share srl | 01/2019 - 05/2019

Mobile iOS, and sometimes Android e crossplatform ReactNative developer, for customer apps, mainly related to the publishing world: Repubblica, Corriere dello Sport, Quattro Ruote, Radio Italia, Gazzetta di Parma, L'Arena, etc.

MOBILE AND BACKEND DEVELOPER

Withepeaks sagl | 11/2017 - 11/2018

Mobile iOS and backend Elixir developer for customer and proprietary apps. Smart contract study and development on Etherium blockchain.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Accenture | 05/2017 - 10/2017

Fullstack Java developer for Unicredit bank.

OTHER SKILLS AND HOBBIES

- Music lover, I play bass guitar and guitar.
- In free time, I often go fishing.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MILAN

Music computer science degree, 2017

- Final valutation: 97/110
- Thesis: Android development of a music real time BPM extractor app.

ISTITUTO TECNICO INDUSTRIALE STATALE "L. GEYMONAT" Scientific high school diploma, 2012.

- Final valutation: 68/100

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Basic english